<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A sermon preached before the Queen at Whitehall on Sunday, Jan. 25, 1690/1 by George Hooper ...</title>
            <author>Hooper, George, 1640-1727.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1691</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 36 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 16 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A44416</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing H2707</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R4458</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13469948</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 13469948</idno>
            <idno type="VID">99675</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A44416)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 99675)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 790:17)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A sermon preached before the Queen at Whitehall on Sunday, Jan. 25, 1690/1 by George Hooper ...</title>
                  <author>Hooper, George, 1640-1727.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 28 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Walter Kettilby ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1691.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"Published by Her Majesty's special command."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Bible. --  N.T. --  Luke XVI, 31 --  Sermons.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>Scott Lepisto</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>Scott Lepisto</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:99675:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A SERMON PREACHED Before the QUEEN, AT WHITEHALL, On <hi>Sunday, Jan.</hi> 25. 1690/1.</p>
            <p>By <hi>GEORGE HOOPER,</hi> D.D. Chaplain in Ordinary to Their MAJESTIES.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Publiſhed by Her Majeſty's Special Command.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Walter Kettilby,</hi> at the <hi>Biſhop</hi>'s <hi>Head</hi> in St. <hi>Paul</hi>'s Church-Yard, 1691.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="sermon">
            <pb facs="tcp:99675:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:99675:2"/>
            <head>A SERMON Preached before the QUEEN.</head>
            <epigraph>
               <q>
                  <bibl>St. LUKE xvi. the laſt Verſe.</bibl>
                  <p>
                     <hi>And he ſaid unto him, If they hear not Moſes and the Prophets, neither will they be perſwaded, though one roſe from the Dead.</hi>
                  </p>
               </q>
            </epigraph>
            <p>THE Tormented Perſon in the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable, after he had in vain requeſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the leaſt degree of refreſhment for himſelf, and had underſtood from <hi>Abraham,</hi> that the <hi>Gulph</hi> was <hi>fix'd,</hi> and the condition of thoſe beyond it without re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>medy; begins then in the next place to inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:99675:3"/>for his neareſt, and yet ſurviving Relati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, his <hi>Brethren</hi> on the Earth; the ſucceſſors to his large Poſſeſſions, and Inheritors, as he fear'd of his Vices; thoſe who fill'd his room in the other World, and might too follow his ſteps hither, and come into the ſame place; but whoſe caſe was not yet deſperate, and for whom a Petition might be granted. He de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſires that <hi>Lazarus</hi> might at leaſt be ſent to them, thoſe to whom he might <hi>paſs,</hi> and they warned not to <hi>come into this place of torment.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This Requeſt, capable of ſeveral interpre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations, appears to ſome, to be made out of the remains of that kindneſs and tenderneſs, which he might have had for his Houſe and Family, though wanting to Strangers and this <hi>Lazarus.</hi> Others ſuppoſe him to conſider him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf and his own Torments, that thoſe already intolerable, might not be yet increas'd, by the growing Guilt his ill Example might be ſtill contracting on the Earth. But it may rather be imagin'd, that under this warning for the future, he couches an excuſe for the paſt; and would inſinuate, that what he deſires for his Brethren, he once wanted himſelf: That he fell into that horrible Miſery for lack of Infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation; and that his Lamentable Condition
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:99675:3"/>deſerv'd therefore much more Compaſſion, than he had beſought.</p>
            <p>So <hi>Abraham</hi> ſeems to underſtand this Petition of the Rich Man, and to ſuch an Intention the Reply of the Patriarch is appoſitely ſuited. He tells him firſt, that his Brethren <hi>had</hi> thoſe al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready, whom they may and ought to <hi>hear,</hi> however they may have been neglected; Great and known, and conſtant Monitors, <hi>Moſes and the Prophets.</hi> And then, when the ſame de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand is ſtill urg'd, and an extraordinary Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monition inſiſted on, to be brought <hi>from the Dead,</hi> as that which in all probability muſt ſucceed: He again anſwers, that ſuch a Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thod may be as Vain and Fruitleſs, as it is un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neceſſary; and peremptorily puts an end to all further Diſcourſe and Expectation with the Words of the Text, <hi>If they hear not</hi> Moſes <hi>and the Prophets, neither will they be perſwaded, though one roſe from the Dead.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>There is another more poſitive meaning, which the words may ſeem to bear at the firſt ſight; That all poſſible Conviction had been already given by <hi>Moſes and the Prophets,</hi> and that one Riſing from the Dead, and particular<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly addreſs'd, would have no more to ſay, nor make any greater Impreſſion. But this cannot
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:99675:4"/>be well admitted: for who can doubt but that ſuch a Perſonal Meſſage would have been a great addition of Evidence and Information; would have deſcrib'd the Torments and Joys, the Puniſhment and Rewards of the other World, not only more lively, but much more plainly, than they had been delivered by <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets? The other ſence therefore I now intimated, is rather to take place; being of it ſelf forcible enough to ſilence the Petiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, or the Complaint, of the Perſon in the Parable: and which you may pleaſe to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider as it conſiſts of theſe three Particulars; The Firſt Abſolute, and that heightned by the Two following Reflections.</p>
            <p>Firſt, That the Notice already given was ſufficient to keep his Brethren from thoſe Tor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments; and that new and greater were unne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſary, and not to be demanded.</p>
            <p>Secondly, That it was not impoſſible, that the deſir'd Warning, if granted, might be neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lected as the other had been.</p>
            <p>And thirdly, Not only poſſibly, but very probably, eſpecially as his Brethren might be diſpos'd, it would be actually ſucceſsleſs.</p>
            <p>Theſe three Particulars, I ſhall ſuppoſe to make up the intire meaning of the Text.</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:99675:4"/>
            <p>The firſt, That the Notice already given was ſufficient, is the imply'd ſence of that part of <hi>Abraham</hi>'s Anſwer, which ſends them to <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets; and is, as we ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe, the foundation of this.</p>
            <p>For as the Rich Man, from the ſtate and courſe of his former Life, might be apt to think, that his Family deſerv'd the honour to be certified by an Expreſs, and was not to be concluded by common notice: ſo, us'd to ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perfluities, he might demand a larger propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Inſtruction for his Brethren, than that which was to ſerve others, the vulgar ſort: an abundance of warning and Evidence, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out which they could no more be inform'd, than they knew how to live without that ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs of wealth in which they had been bred. But here the extravagance of this his Requeſt is reſtrain'd, and reduc'd to its true bounds: He is told, That there is a Competence of Knowledge, as well as of Fortune; That God's Providence had already afforded them a libe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral ſhare of Inſtruction, enough for their occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions, and with which they ought to be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tented, imploying it to its true uſe; That ſuch idle demands were infinite and impertinent; That this ſort of Covetouſneſs was not to be ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfied
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:99675:5"/>neither; and that none more uſually call'd for more, than thoſe who had before too much.</p>
            <p>It is indeed true, and the inſtance is before us: The unequal diſtribution of Worldly Goods, that ſets ſome in redundant Plenty, may reduce others, and thoſe not the leaſt deſerving, to want of neceſſaries in this Life. And this diſproportion, we know, can no way better be reconcil'd to Divine Juſtice, than by a future Diſcrimination, the Judgment of the World to come: which Judgment therefore, this Perſon and his Brethren might have col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lected, if only from a view of themſelves and that <hi>Lazarus.</hi> But that juſt Diſcrimination, we likewiſe preſume will be ſo ordered, that none ſhall ſuffer in that day, by the unequal diſtribution of knowledge now; nor be ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>countable for more, than had been before committed. It ſhall appear in the ſcantieſt diſpenſation of thoſe Talents, that our Maſter is not <hi>hard, expecting to reap where he has not ſown, or to gather where he has not ſtraw'd;</hi> that he that had receiv'd leaſt, enjoyed however enough to have kept him from that dreadful place.</p>
            <p>That Man therefore lay now Tormented,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:99675:5"/>not for lack of Advertiſement, but Attention: nor for any failure of God, but for his own. Neither does he here beg, as <hi>Lazarus</hi> did here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tofore, for the ſupply of any real want; he cannot pretend that his Brethren are under ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſity, or ſo much as that they had been nar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rowly and ſparingly dealt with; to whom Providence had been ſo bountiful, even in that kind, in thoſe ſignal and multiplied Notices, wherewith his Family and whole Nation were enrich'd above the reſt of Men.</p>
            <p>Had he and his Brethren been ſtrangers to this <hi>Abraham,</hi> and never heard of <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets; yet they had not remain'd unin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form'd of the great Duties of Life, and thoſe for the tranſgreſſion of which he now ſuffers. The Being to be acknowledg'd and worſhipp'd, had not <hi>left himſelf without a Witneſs,</hi> if theſe had never <hi>teſtified: the inviſible things of him, his Power and Godhead, being to be underſtood,</hi> not from the Words of a Meſſage, but <hi>from the things that were made.</hi> The Obligations too of Tempe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance Juſtice, and Charity, had been ſuffici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ently diſcover'd, from the Light of Reaſon, and Dictates of Humane Nature. The Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctates I ſay of Nature, or the innate Notions of the Mind; taking leave to uſe theſe words
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:99675:6"/>in the common way of Speech, and as they ſerve to expreſs, that moral ſence, that diſtin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive faculty of Good and Ill, to which, acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons of Juſtice, and Beneficence, and Gratitude, are Natural and Delightful, and the contrary Diſtaſtful and Diſagreeable, by the frame and make of our ſpiritual Part. As Taſts, or Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lours, or Sounds, are to the Palate, the Eye, or the Ear, by the Providence of God in the Fabrick of the Body: So is it that the <hi>work of the Law is written in mens hearts,</hi> as the Apoſtle phraſes it. Hence the <hi>Conſciences</hi> of the Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>then are inſtructed to <hi>accuſe or excuſe:</hi> And ſo would theſe men have been without excuſe, had they been without thoſe Notices from their Law-giver. The Commandment, of whoſe violation they ſtand guilty, needs no new De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claration now; it was not neceſſary, it ſhould have been proclaim'd from Mount <hi>Sinai.</hi> Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore <hi>that day it was not hidden from man, nor afar off: It was not in Heaven, that he ſhould ſay, who ſhall go up for him to Heaven, and bring it unto him, that he may hear it, and do it? neither was it beyond the Sea;</hi> (to uſe <hi>Moſes</hi>'s words, even concerning the unwritten Law:) It was not to be ſent from beyond this Gulph; nor was it one of the ſecrets of Hell, or Heaven. <hi>The Word was
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:99675:6"/>very nigh unto him, in his Mouth, and in his Heart, that he ſhould do it:</hi> It was what his own Heart conceiv'd to be right and juſt, and what his Mouth was ready to pronounce, at leaſt in the caſe of others.</p>
            <p>But beyond this, theſe were the Sons of <hi>A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>braham:</hi> He is call'd upon as their Father in this Diſtreſs, and was heretofore their boaſt. His Faith, and his Hoſpitality, were their Glory; and ſhould have been their example: From him they made themſelves a Title to the Bleſſings and Friendſhip of Heaven; and if they follow'd not his ſteps, what could they expect but its Enmity and Indignation? that In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>juſtice, Uncharitableneſs, and Luxury, ſhould be attended by the Fate of <hi>Sodom,</hi> and puniſh'd by ſuch Fire? ſhould no more be reliev'd now, than they were ſpar'd of old, at <hi>Abraham</hi>'s im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portunate Interceſſion?</p>
            <p>And yet further, to paſs over the ſeveral Revelations made to the Patriarchs, and which were to deſcend to their Off-ſpring, as their beſt Inheritance; at laſt, from the Mount, a general and wonderful Declaration was made, to which the Miracles of <hi>Aegypt</hi> had prepar'd, as thoſe of the Wilderneſs did atteſt. Then the Natural Law of Mens Breaſts was tranſcrib'd,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:99675:7"/>and exemplified by the hand of God, to be read in the Tables of Stone, and Books of <hi>Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes;</hi> no longer whiſper'd from within, in ſilent, gentle Commands, but loudly and terribly proclaim'd, in a Voice of Thunder, too au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dible not to be <hi>heard;</hi> and at which they could not but tremble, had the Earth ſtood unmov'd; the delivery of their Duty accompanied with horrour, and ſpeaking the diſmal conſequences of its neglect.</p>
            <p>So did God himſelf continue to <hi>teſtify</hi> to that Generation, by his Servant <hi>Moſes;</hi> nor did he ceaſe to admoniſh their Poſterity by his Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets: all whoſe Writings were tranſmitted down, receiv'd by the Jews, and read every day in their Synagogues; ſtill denouncing Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vine Wrath againſt Exceſs, Rapine, Oppreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion and Unmercifulneſs, as the Rich Man may now too late remember.</p>
            <p>This <hi>Moſes</hi> and thoſe Prophets he had <hi>heard</hi> in the Synagogue; his quality, no doubt, had preferr'd him to read them there. Well skill'd in the Law, it may be, he was, and the Ora<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cle of his Country; a Zealot poſſibly for his Religion, againſt the <hi>Samaritan,</hi> or the Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>then: But ſtill he was to learn to <hi>bear;</hi> he had not heard them to the purpoſe they ſpoke, and
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:99675:7"/>with that attention which the importance and weight of the Meſſage requir'd: he had lent them the Ear, in manner, or for ſhow, but he had hearkned to the temptation of Pleaſure, or Propoſitions of Honour and Gain.</p>
            <p>It may be he had <hi>heard</hi> them wantonly or maliciouſly; to make mirth and deride, or to cavil and object: Happy for ever, in his Jeſt; and ſecure, if he could but doubt. The Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port of ſo many Miracles might have only taught him to demand one; that he ſhould be as much conſider'd as his Forefathers, and have a wonder beſtow'd upon him; reſolv'd not to believe without Evidence of the firſt hand, as great as he ſhould fanſie, or God could give.</p>
            <p>And it was true, that greater Evidence might have been given. If God had ſo pleas'd, Faith no doubt might have loſt its name, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come Science: The Godhead might have ſhin'd out like the Sun, and his Pleaſure as clear as the Noon-day. And ſo the Body of Man might have been wing'd, been cloath'd, and arm'd by Nature; endow'd with other Sences, as much ſurpaſſing our ſight, as that does the dulleſt of the five; and made obnoxious nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther to Pain nor Death: and, as our Mind, might have been created incapable of Error, or of Sin.</p>
            <pb n="12" facs="tcp:99675:8"/>
            <p>But God is <hi>he that made us, and not we our ſelves.</hi> He is to preſcribe to us, not we to him: He not being accountable, for what he with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holds; but we, for what we have receiv'd. We are thankfully to be content with the day he has diſpens'd, with ſo much light as he holds out, and at the diſtance he has plac'd it: enjoying the direction, and not quarrelling at the Spots of his Sun. The proviſions for this Life, and for the other, are left to our Care, and recommended to our induſtry: and Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon is given us to work out of that ſtock which is afforded us, whether Material or Intellectu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al, not only our Preſervation in this World, but our Salvation in the Next. That Reaſon we are to make uſe of, as we do of our ſight, though it be limitted and obſcure, and ſubject to deception: not therefore becoming Brutes, becauſe we are not made Intelligent as Angels. And the Knowledge that God imparts of Him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf and his Will, though not the Brighteſt, nor moſt Perfect, we are to lay hold on, and to cultivate, as proportion'd to our Capacity, and ſufficient for the End; not ſtanding upon Terms, and refuſing to perceive, becauſe he is not pleas'd Mathematically to demonſtrate. God is not oblig'd, to act for us to the Extent
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:99675:8"/>of his Omnipotence; but it is we who are bound in Duty to Him, to the utmoſt of our Endeavours.</p>
            <p>To complain of our Bountiful Maker, is un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>juſt, and highly ungrateful: but to recrimi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate upon him, and to charge him with our Faults, will be a very bold and a fatal De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence; a Plea more guilty, than all our former Preſumptions; and which will not prevent, but finiſh our Condemnation. Such an impu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation as this, though covertly offer'd, <hi>Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham</hi> in the Parable cut ſhort: a Reflection not to be born by the Servants of God, by <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets. They had not fail'd to teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fy, and had diſcharg'd their Office: but theſe Brethren (may they ſay,) theſe for whom more Revelation is ask'd, what of their known duty have they done? Do they act in proportion to what they have already from us? Or do they live as Men, and ſuch as were indued with Reaſon? Do they indeed deſire a clearer Evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence? Or, for the ſake of their belov'd Vices, do they not rather dread a convincing Diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very? Thoſe who have neglected ſo much warning, how little do they deſerve more? or to what purpoſe ſhould it be given? That Rich Man muſt confeſs, that all the Inſupport<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:99675:9"/>Torment he labours under, he endures not for any Tranſgreſſion Involuntary, and of which he was not abundantly premoniſh'd: He had too much warning given him, and therefore thoſe Coals of Fire are ſo heap'd. He does therefore in truth make a very dangerous requeſt for his Brethren, and out of favour to them it may be deny'd by <hi>Abraham:</hi> More knowledge perhaps may only help to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demn them more; and put them into a worſe place, than that in which he himſelf lies. If <hi>Lazarus,</hi> added to <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets, can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not <hi>Perſwade</hi> them; he will be join'd then on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly to <hi>Teſtify</hi> againſt them. And this is the Poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſibility the Text imports in the ſecond place, and which we are now going to conſider.</p>
            <p n="2">II. <hi>If they hear not</hi> Moſes <hi>and the Prophets, neither</hi> [Poſſibly] <hi>will they be perſwaded, though one roſe,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Should God be pleas'd to change his De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creed Methods, the Sacred Order of his All<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe Providence, for the ſake of this Family; to expoſe more of his Mercy and Goodneſs to ſuch unworthy Affronts; ſhould <hi>Lazarus</hi> be content to leave the <hi>Boſom of Abraham,</hi> and the Happineſs of Heaven, to go once more upon the miſerable Earth, and to thoſe inhoſpitable
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:99675:9"/>Doors: What aſſurance has this Perſon to give, that the Meſſenger ſhall be heard, or that the Divine Endeavours ſhall not be again fruſtrated, and meet with another Repulſe? Will he ty caution for the ſucceſs, and anſwer for the expence of the Miracle? Be contented that this Trial ſhould be made, and God tempted and wearied, at his further Peril?</p>
            <p>No doubt but thoſe of the Gentiles too that are in Hell, thoſe from <hi>Tyre</hi> or <hi>Sidon,</hi> who are guilty of the ſame Crimes, are condemn'd, in proportion to their knowledge, to the like Torment; no doubt, I ſay, but thoſe, full of the ſenſe of their preſent Miſery, and for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>getting the powerful influence of paſt Plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſures, may likewiſe lament their own unhappy Lot, and vainly wiſh, that they had been bleſs'd with the opportunity of ſome more ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſs Information; that ſome ſingle Prophet had been addreſs'd to their Fathers, with the leaſt verbal Intimation from their Maker; had ſuch Revelations deſcended to them, their Duty ſo clearly explain'd, and ſo movingly in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forc'd, how Attentive and Obedient ſhould they have been, never certainly have come in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to <hi>this Place.</hi> Amaz'd they may be at the Neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligence or Infidelity of this Jew; and ſubſcribe
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:99675:10"/>to the Divine Sentence, <hi>that His Damnation is juſt.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But this Son of <hi>Abraham</hi> ſenſibly knows, how much miſtaken ſuch conceits are, and how little Extraordinary Advertiſements and plain Declarations may be able to effect. He can tell them, that not only the Light of Reaſon may be eſteem'd an <hi>Ignis Fatuus,</hi> and its di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctates nothing but Education and Prepoſſeſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, at leaſt be eaſily obſcur'd and over-rul'd: but that other ſupernatural and clearer infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mations may be entertain'd with the ſame Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judices, ſtirr'd up at the ſollicitation of Mens Luſts or Intereſts; may be alike neglected and thrown by, or cavill'd at, ſlighted and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demn'd: that the paſt Revelations may be turn'd into Fables, and the Preſent into Dreams. This Perſon therefore may eaſily reflect, from the Practice of his Nation, and his own Life, that new Obedience is not always inferr'd from new Notice; and may himſelf beſt conceive, what ſort of reception <hi>Lazarus</hi> may find. Whatever wonder on the Earth his Appear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance may be, it will be none there; ſhould the Meſſage he brings miſcarry, much Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe and Diſpute may be rais'd upon it; but no Reformation follow.</p>
            <pb n="17" facs="tcp:99675:10"/>
            <p>And ſo might this Apparition be look'd on by the Friends of his Houſe, as a Phantome only and Illuſion, the ſickneſs of ſome Melan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cholick and diſtemper'd Imagination. How can a Man return again from the Grave? And how came that Beggar to be ſent? Had <hi>Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham</hi> no other to take into his Boſom, and to imploy to his chiefeſt Sons? Let them not diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grace their Family by ſuch an Ignominious re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port concerning their Brother, and brought by ſuch a Meſſenger. For if Angels and Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rits, in the Philoſophy of thoſe times, had the favour to be allow'd a Being; yet what ſhould this be, but ſome wandring one of the Air, falſely pretending to a higher Sphere: The old Vagabond, that has no certain place of Reſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence now; and comes out of Envy or Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lice, to haunt and diſturb the Happy. Some Banquet therefore, or other divertive Enter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainment was to be provided, to chear up this Melancholy; ſome more real and better Company than a Ghoſt; and part of the ill<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>got Riches to be ſpent in the defence of the reſt. So very poſſibly might this returning <hi>Lazarus</hi> be no more harkned to now when <hi>Teſtifying,</hi> than before when Begging.</p>
            <p>But little might this Viſion be minded after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards,
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:99675:11"/>however regarded at firſt; the thoughts and apprehenſions of it, vaniſhing in ſome time, and following the ſhadow: ſo that if it was not reputed a Dream, yet it might paſs away like one; and the Image of it by degrees grow faint, and diſappear, effac'd by the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant force of other ſenſible impreſſions, from more agreeable and ſtill preſent objects. Scar'd his Brethren might be at firſt, and diſorder'd; but at length recover, return to themſelves, and their old Courſe; brought firſt to neglect, then to forget, and may be at laſt to disbelieve, even what had appear'd unto themſelves.</p>
            <p>Such effects as theſe, though ſtrange in ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culation, yet are frequent in Practice; com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly wrought, by our ſtupid addiction to the Preſent, by the charms of Pleaſure, the careleſsneſs of the Mind, and the willfullneſs of our Paſſions. And ſo we know, that re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peated Admonitions from Friends or Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrates, and miſerable or terrible Examples, are not of force to diſſwade ſome Men, from falling under the ſame Calamities, and incur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring the like Condemnation. Notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing all that can be advis'd or proclaim'd, there are thoſe who will continue the ſame rui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nous Prodigality and Exceſs, and venture up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:99675:11"/>the ſame raſh and criminal attempts; go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing on gaily and unconcernedly, to loſe their Health, their Eſtate, or Life; till they be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come at laſt Examples and Warnings them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, as little to be regarded by others, and as certainly neglected in their turns.</p>
            <p>The ghaſtly ſight of a dying Friend, may chill our blood, and ſtrike us with ſerious Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flections; make ſome change upon our Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenance, and on our Minds; but when we go back among the living World, we are ſoon engag'd in the Faſhion of it; quickly forget the Deceas'd, and our own Mortality; again contrive and deſign, as if we were left behind to continue here for ever. All Monuments and <hi>Memento</hi>'s are ineffectual to the purpoſe they ſpeak: and ſo many going to the dead, can not well <hi>perſwade</hi> us that we ſhall follow.</p>
            <p>Nay ſome there are, that have been them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves among the <hi>Dead;</hi> that in ſome danger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Sickneſs have been ſo near this place, as to have had a lively view of it; and, in the bitterneſs of their Soul, almoſt to have felt its torments: and what firm Reſolutions do they then make? What ſolemn Promiſes to God, and to themſelves? which yet give place, when health and vigour returns; the forgetful Crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:99675:12"/>relapſing in a little time into his old ſins, and not having been perſwaded, no not by his own Convictions.</p>
            <p>Inſomuch that if we ſhould ſuppoſe <hi>Abraham</hi> to procure a greater favour for this Perſon, than he knew how to deſire; to take him out of that Flame, and ſet him again on the Earth; not for ſome temporary care, while he is up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on a ſhort Errand; but for another Trial of his Obedience, and a new opportunity of de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livering himſelf out of that intolerable State: Upon this ſuppoſition, impracticable indeed as he is told by <hi>Abraham,</hi> it would not however be impracticable to imagine, that this very perſon might by degrees fall into his former Errors, and ſlide into the Way that will bring him back into the ſame Place; like ſome par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don'd Criminals, that are ſtill under Bonds to their old Vice, and ſoon deſerve a ſecond Sen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence. So little therefore can this Man be confident of the ſucceſs of a Report upon his Brethren, that perchance his own Experience might not prove Warning enough unto Him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf.</p>
            <p>Were not the Inſtances of theſe difficult and unperſwaſible tempers ſo frequent in humane Life, innumerable might be brought from
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:99675:12"/>ſacred ſtory: <hi>Pharaoh</hi> not perſwaded by ten Miracles, and to be drown'd by another: The Children of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> whoſe hardneſs of heart as much exceeded his, as the power of <hi>Moſes</hi> did that of his Magicians; thoſe the peculiar People of God, inform'd from his Mouth, led and fed by daily Miracles, and yet giving no Credence to his Word; <hi>a froward Generation, Children in whom there was no Faith;</hi> as their Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giver deſcribes them. To conclude, the Holy Books are full of Admonition, from God, and of the Diſobedience of Men: Warning us from our Sins, and from any great hopes of grow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing better by new warnings; for this too is a Leſſon that may be learnt from <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets.</p>
            <p>And thus we have ſeen the aſſertion of the Text to be ſo poſſible, that there is great rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon to proceed higher, and to underſtand it more poſitively; as that which would gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rally happen in the World, and may very <hi>Probably</hi> be verified on thoſe Brethren: the laſt and the full ſence of the Words.</p>
            <p>III. <hi>If they hear not Moſes and the Prophets,</hi> neither will they <hi>be perſwaded,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>This Intractableneſs in many, and Infide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity to <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets, is not oppos'd
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:99675:13"/>particularly to their Perſons, nor only able to over-balance their Teſtimony: it is generally ready to encounter the ſame grievous Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands, whoever brings them; and ſtrong enough to repulſe another Meſſenger. It has learnt from over-ruling greater and more illu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrious Evidence, eaſily to defeat this: and <hi>Lazarus</hi> muſt yield, where <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets could not prevail.</p>
            <p>The Miracles indeed of thoſe days are long paſt, and <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets were Men of old; (and let us ſuppoſe them to be Antiqua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, and to need this Reinforcement:) but the Unbelief of that time was Humane, and Natu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral, and has been propagated to the preſent Age; The <hi>Iſraelite,</hi> the crooked and perverſe Generation, ſtill continues; the wantonneſs and frowardneſs of ſuch, as will not have God for their King. The Rich Man, <hi>if he inquires wiſely, will not ſay, that the former days were</hi> worſe <hi>than theſe.</hi> There are the ſame Diſpoſitions now, of whom the like may be preſum'd, and where Miracles would be beſtow'd in vain: Men whoſe underſtandings are darkned, and Conſciences ſear'd; who have already done that violence to their inward better part, that they are grown Inſenſible of any thing that
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:99675:13"/>comes againſt their preſent Intereſt, and from another World: The advice to the Sceptick would be falſe and viſionary, dull and nauſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous, to the Man of Pleaſure; and to the Man of Buſineſs, trifling and impertinent; the Ghoſtly Friend an Enemy to them and to their Deſigns, as unwelcome as Satan, and to be Exorcis'd. For ſtill it is, that thoſe who have devoted themſelves to the Idols of this World, Pleaſures, Riches, or Honour, look upon all diſcourſe offer'd againſt their Deities as Blaſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phemy: accordingly they <hi>throw duſt in the air,</hi> to blind their Eyes; they ſtop their Ears, and cry <hi>away with it, running on with one accord.</hi> Theſe are properly ſaid to be dead in ſin, not to be reſtor'd by any Remedy, however powerful and extraordinary, that works by moral force; whom God indeed may make ſenſible, and raiſe by his Omnipotence, as he may now re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn <hi>Lazarus:</hi> but upon whom this <hi>Lazarus,</hi> ſo remanded by Miracle, will not operate, except he brings with him the power of Miracles, and can confer Grace, ſuch as ſhall not be reſiſted.</p>
            <p>And thus there might be Sons of <hi>Abraham,</hi> of whom this Sentence might be true in its ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vereſt meaning: and of thoſe, this Rich Man might be one; and he by it given to under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand,
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:99675:14"/>that he himſelf would not have been perſwaded by the wonder he deſires; and nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther will his Brethren be, thoſe of the ſame Family and Mind.</p>
            <p>And ſo might the miſerable Jew be well ſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lenc'd by this reaſonable and righteous An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer, and he and his Brethren left without ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſe: ſuch as they ſhould alledge in earneſt, and at the Day of Account; not indeed with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out ſuch excuſes as better deſerve that name, frivolous and falſe pretences, rais'd by the lazy or the obſtinate; childiſh pleas of affected Ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norance, and counterfeit Diſability, ſuch as God in his Government of the World will not conſider, nor does any humane Magiſtracy admit. Juſtified will our Creator be in his ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and Sentence; and clear when he is judg'd, and when he judges.</p>
            <p>This Anſwer of <hi>Abraham,</hi> grounded upon Obſervation of common Life, and the practice of the Jews, has been ſince eminently con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firm'd by the experiment of Chriſtianity. Our Saviour, <hi>the Brightneſs of God's Glory, and the ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſs Image of his Perſon,</hi> has himſelf brought down Information to us, infinitely ſurpaſſing what was <hi>ſpoke to the Fathers by</hi> Moſes <hi>and the Prophets:</hi> has laid open to us the World to
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:99675:14"/>come, and given the free proſpect of Heaven and Hell; declar'd more of the Future State in this ſingle Parable, than was to be read in all thoſe Writings to which <hi>Abraham</hi> refers. What too is ſaid here to be denied, he did ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect; and rais'd one <hi>Lazarus</hi> from the Grave. And when by that reſcue of another from Death, he had only haſtned his own; (His very Diſciples not ſo well <hi>perſwaded</hi> by that, and ſo many other Miracles, as not to forſake; nay to deny him:) he was pleas'd himſelf to riſe from the Dead, finally to inſtruct and to warn Men. This Goſpel he Commiſſion'd choſen Men to publiſh, and impower'd them to confirm it with Signs and Wonders: Mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titudes of his Servants continually declaring, by the zeal of the Lives and the conſtancy of their Death, the truth of their Maſter's Reſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection, and their aſſurance of their own. By ſuch evident Teſtimonies, the World found it ſelf oblig'd to admit and to confeſs his Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctrine: but neither is it ſo <hi>perſwaded.</hi> It <hi>hears,</hi> and pretends to believe; but goes on ſtill in its old courſe, and lives after the Unchriſtian manner: ſometimes it wants a ſign, or an in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fallible Proponent, or a ſcientifick demonſtra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; glad to know how to except and object,
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:99675:15"/>and reſolv'd not to obey: not to be fully per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwaded, it ſeems, ſhould all the Dead ariſe, or the whole Hoſt of Heaven come down.</p>
            <p>So true has this Affirmation of <hi>Abraham</hi>'s ſince prov'd; and ſo little Faith has our Savi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our found: At his Death he left not much, and he makes it a queſtion after, whether at his return he ſhall find any; any proportionable to the clearneſs of the Meſſage, and to the Greatneſs and Dignity of the Reporter. The Event, he has not only intimated in the Para<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, but foretold expreſly: neither is the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>velation he has made, diſparag'd, but verified by it. We are not ſurpriz'd to find, that there are ſuch who neglect or contradict. Theſe are thoſe of whom we have been warn'd, thoſe that <hi>will not be perſwaded;</hi> neither ſhould any give themſelves the vain pleaſure, to think that they can diſgrace the Goſpel, or diſappoint its Author: His word will certainly ſerve, to the purpoſe to which it was ordain'd; and his honour is as ſecure as his Happineſs: It is the Unbeliever only who will ſuffer.</p>
            <p>The Notice we have is ſo plain and evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent, that reaſonably and in duty we cannot demand more: however more will not be granted. If the <hi>ſign of Jonas</hi> has not had any
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:99675:15"/>effect, <hi>no other ſhall be given:</hi> nor any more riſe from the Dead, till we our ſelves do to Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. The Book is ſeal'd, as the Gulph be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low is fix'd: and thoſe that will not be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vail'd with by this method, <hi>they will not,</hi> they ſhall not, by any other. If they will not hear <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets, the Son of God and his Apoſtles; there will be no further endea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour to perſwade them: If the Goſpel be hid, it is hid to thoſe that are loſt.</p>
            <p>Make we uſe therefore of the laſt and only Help; a greater than which we cannot, we muſt not, hope for. Take we heed how we deſpiſe the Admonition of him that is Riſen from the Dead, and now <hi>ſpeaks from Heaven; who will once more ſhake not the Earth only;</hi> our Maker, our Redeemer, and our Judge.</p>
            <p>This Life is the time to <hi>hear</hi> the Directions of God, and to comply with his deſign for our Salvation: hereafter we ſhall be only call'd to <hi>hear</hi> his Sentence, and to confeſs its Juſtice. And then a knowing Age, will be the moſt improper to plead Ignorance: nor will a Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtian of this Country, dare to ſay, that he wanted Notice.</p>
            <p>The Aſſertion of the Parable concerning the Unbelief of Men, we ſee how true and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>act
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:99675:16" rendition="simple:additions"/>it is: as really fullfill'd will the Narrative part be concerning its Conſequence and Iſſue. The <hi>perſwaded,</hi> and the <hi>unperſwaded,</hi> will then have their different Portions, and be ſet at a wide diſtance: And we ſhall all hereafter be, in the condition of this Unhappy Perſon, or of that <hi>Lazarus;</hi> either <hi>Comforted,</hi> or <hi>Tormented.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>God grant that, according to that other Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable, our Improvement may be, in propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion to the number of our multiplied Talents: and that we may ſo hear all our other warn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings, and this preſent Admonition, that we may be found with Faithful <hi>Abraham</hi> in the Joy of our Maſter: To whom with the Holy Ghoſt, be all Honour and Glory, now and for Ever.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
